Devin Baughman

502 N. Minor Ave. East Wenatchee, WA

+1 (509) 699-6161 :: devbau1993@gmail.com :: linkedin.com/in/devin-baughman/

Summary

A compassionate individual that loves computer programming, technology integration and spreading knowledge of how amazing these devices we use is! I work with computers in my career path along with self-learning daily in server and container technology. In my career, I have worked professionally with applications that handle 10000+ users a day and require lean, clean, safe, efficient code to work correctly. I've been on the front line of support and been along the whole process of being notified of a bug, documenting the bug, testing the bug, and fixing the bug in the source code to deploy for the user to enjoy!

Skills

- Server Administration
- Hyper-Visor Administration
- Containerd
- Version Controls; git, svn
- REST Tools; curl, insomnia
- Scheduling; cronjob
- Automated Testing; Selenium
- C# Dotnet
- JavaScript
- Relational Databasing
- Rust
- Friendly
- Detail oriented
- Team player
- Resourceful
- Dedicated

Work history

Junior Software Developer - 01/2022 to 03/2023

Applied Innovation Inc., East Wenatchee, WA/Hybrid Remote Receive Jira items relative to a Bug or Additional functionality wanted in 1 of 3 of our platforms. I would probe the Jira item for any additional hints or information that could glean on where I could find this functionality in source. I would go directly to where I can stress test this functionality within the application itself. Once I've pinpointed where I know the functionality or bug exists within the application from a user perspective I can then check the developer tools to find relative controls that I am interacting with in the User space. When I can find the identifiers for the controls that I'm interacting with I will than do a full search of the Application's source code for the control's identifier, I can than run locally and with Visual Studio breakpoints I can verify that I am in the correct location where I need to be relative to my Jira ticket.

Technical Support and Training - 07/2021 to 03/2023

Applied Innovation Inc., East Wenatchee, WA/Hybrid Remote Proactively monitor incoming emails and phone calls relative to support inquiry. These support issues can vary greatly dependent on the users infrastructure and there is no 1 true standard for how the clients system is configured and setup. I have 4 in-house main platforms;Conduit - File Transfer software provided by us, Client Access Web - Portal for our client base, PayStream - Financial portal for our clients' clients to utilize, and Papyrus - Document manager integrated into ClientAccessWeb and PayStream, that I must understand and be able to take low level knowledge to a very high end user language. I lead training our new clients on proper use of our applications and fit functionality into their business needs in the moment, these could be business owners, system administrators, or even collectors and would offer training anytime via Zoom, GoTo Meetings, Teams or any other software that fits the clients needs.

Technical Support – 09/2020 - 07/2021

Wenatchee Valley College, Wenatchee, WA

Monitor incoming emails and phone calls relative to support, handle in person on campus on via remote using built-in Active Directory Tools. Hardware fixes relative to Dell Optiplex desktops, Latitude and Precision laptops, diagnosing and replacing corrupted drives, old RAM, laptop panel replacements, and UEFI configuration issues. Administered WAN installations, mass PXE boots across whole classrooms, AD user policy administration and configuration of faculty devices. Worked with ensuring correct sub nets and VLAN's are associated with the correct classrooms relative to Student, Faculty or Administration VLAN, this also tied into correct PXE boot image coming from DHCP based on that VLAN.

Education

Bachelor of Computer Science: Western Governors University, 2023 – Present Associate of Information Technology: Wenatchee Valley College, 2019 - 2021